Paul DeCarlo

Sr. Software Development Engineer at Microsoft

Summary

Paul DeCarlo is a Microsoft Technology Evangelist and Professor for the Bauer College of Business at the University of Houston. His current technology interests focus on Internet of Things, Cloud Applications, and Cross-Platform mobile app development. He is also an experienced startup founder for WinCoder LLC (http://wincoder.co) which focuses on Windows application development, including Searchler (Web, Windows Phone, and Windows 8), a Pandora type service for Music Videos operating on a hybrid Apache and IIS instance in Microsoft Azure. On weekends Paul performs as lead vocalist in Houston's Tool Tribute band - Spiral Out (spiraloutband.com)

Microsoft MVP nominee (2012)

Microsoft Bizpark startup member.

For a full listing of completed projects and code portfolio see my resume @

http://wincoder.co/PaulDeCarloCV.pdf

Specialties: Software development, Windows Phone, Windows 8, WPF, .NET, startup experience, marketing, business strategy

Experience

Senior Software Development Engineer at Microsoft

March 2017 - Present

The role of a Software Development Engineer within Microsoft's Developer Experience team consists of building compelling tools and use cases through individual and customer engagements which focus on emerging technology platforms. Current endeavors include cognitive services for AI as a service, cloud deployments, Mobile development, Dev Ops, and Data Visualization.

Adjunct Professor at University of Houston

January 2014 - Present

Instruct Cloud-Driven Mobile Application Development as part of the Management Information Systems track in the Bauer College of Business. This course covers: (a) Cloud Services for Mobile Devices --The primary technology being the Microsoft Azure Platform and focus on Windows Azure Mobile Services; (b) Cross Platform Development – Design considerations and code sharing techniques used in developing

apps which target multiple platforms. The primary technology focus will being Visual Studio, Blend, and Portable Class Libraries; (c) Publishing applications to a digital marketplace – How to submit an application for certification in the Windows Phone 8 and Windows 8 stores.

Windows Phone / Windows 8 Developer at Wincoder LLC

March 2011 - Present

Windows Phone / Windows 8 / Web Development startup. Currently offering multiple application brands in the Windows Phone 7 marketplace ranging from music/video aggregators, earthquake monitoring, and facebook/twitter interaction. Over 500,000 applications downloaded. Utilize C# .NET 4.0, WPF, Blend, and XNA.

Creator of top-music-videos.com. Music aggregrator site which uses itunes sales data to autopopulate videos for 23 country categories with 20 genres each for a total of 460 categories. This app has been branded on the WP7 for each country. Notables include our Greek app at #3, Israel app at #2 and Japan app at #2 in the music + video category on the Zune marketplace. Website utilizes php, javascript, html, flash, bash code configured on Centos 5.6 running apache and mysql.

Technology Evangelist at Microsoft

March 2013 - March 2017 (4 years 1 month)

The role of Technology Evangelist requires delivering information, support, training, and representation of Microsoft's latest technology stack to an audience of developers, students, professionals, and decision makers. At this time, I focus on helping partners produce applications on the Windows 10, Windows Phone, and Microsoft Azure platforms with a specialization on Internet of Things cloud-connected solutions.

Technical Professional-Software Development at Halliburton

January 2011 - March 2013 (2 years 3 months)

Member of the Production Enhancement team in Houston, TX. Work related to software development of a product for complex fracture modeling using realtime geoseismic data. Code scenarios for simulating real-time communication of microseismic event data from the field to the office. Utilize C# .Net 4.0, Visual Studio Load Test, Coded UI, WPF, Blend, Visual Studio Test Controller/Agent rig deployment.

ASUS Campus Representative at University of Houston

August 2010 - July 2011 (1 year)

Promoted the ASUS product line at campus events. Provided market research to guide product development. Won numerous competitions to drive users to social media driven marketing campaigns.

Microsoft Student Partner at University of Houston

January 2010 - July 2011 (1 year 7 months)

Provide training and support for Microsoft Products in development. Created a server laboratory which utilizes Microsoft Developer Network software and tools as a teaching platform. Worked to introduce

the Windows Phone 7 mobile platform as a new course at the University of Houston. Mentored game development teams competing in the Microsoft Imagine Cup.

Consulting Partner

October 2009 - December 2010 (1 year 3 months)

Develop and implement network solutions for small to medium based businesses. Elicit requirements from entities and participate in the configuration process. Recently completed a network based computer re-imaging deployment system which relies on an Achronis imaging server, serving across a Cisco Catalyst 2900 Fiber port to 23 client computers. See it in action here: http://www.youtube.com/watch? v=pr_aS10g7Y8

Graduate Student at University of Houston

January 2009 - December 2010 (2 years)

Focus on data mining and machine learning concepts. Thesis work describes using data mining techniques to establish the knowledge base of a custom developed expert system / inference engine to be in used in education evaluation. Produced two publications directly related to thesis work and presented at Columbia University and the University of Madrid. Work currently appears in the Journal of Advanced Corporate Learning.

Instructed Introductory Computer Science and Introductory Computer Organization and Design Principles at a college institution. Video lectures of all courses taught are available at http://www.screencast.com/users/pjdecarlo/

Education

University of Houston

MS, Computer Science, 2008 - 2010

Activities and Societies: CougarCS Vice President of Corporate Relations, President of Concrete 5 web development, Open Knowledge, Undergraduate tutor for Computer Science Department **University of Houston**

BS, Psychology with Minor in Business, 2004 - 2006

Activities and Societies: Student Government Association CLASS Senator, Psi-Chi National Honors Society, Founder and Vice President of Theta Xi Alpha Omicron Chapter, Black Belt in United States Taekwondo Alliance

Paul DeCarlo

Sr. Software Development Engineer at Microsoft



Contact Paul on LinkedIn